So I'm a woman with chronic schizophrenia.
أنا امرأة أعاني من مرض انفصام الشخصية المزمن.
I've spent hundreds of days
قضيت مئات الأيام
in psychiatric hospitals.
في مستشفيات الأمراض النفسية.
I might have ended up spending
وربما انتهى بي الأمر بقضاء
most of my life on the back ward of a hospital,
معظم حياتي في جناح الخلفي للمستشفى،
but that isn't how my life turned out.
لكن حياتي لم تتحول هكذا.
In fact, I've managed to stay clear of hospitals
في الواقع، لقد تمكنت من البقاء دون المستشفيات
for almost three decades,
لما يقرب ثلاثة عقود،
perhaps my proudest accomplishment.
ربما يُعد هذا هو انجازي الأفخر.
That's not to say that I've remained clear
وهذا لا يعني أنني قد انتهيت
of all psychiatric struggles.
من كل الصراعات النفسية.
After I graduated from the Yale Law School and
بعد أن تخرجت من كلية الحقوق في جامعة ييل و
got my first law job, my New Haven analyst, Dr. White,
حصلت على وظيفتي الأولى في الحقوق، عند محلل نيو هافن، الدكتور وايت،
announced to me that he was going to close his practice
قال لي أنه سوف يغلق مكتبه
in three months, several years
بعد ثلاثة أشهر، قبل عدة سنوات
before I had planned to leave New Haven.
من تخطيطي لمغادرة نيو هافن.
White had been enormously helpful to me,
كان د. وايت يدعمني بشدة،
and the thought of his leaving
و التفكير بمغادرته
shattered me.
حطمني
My best friend Steve,
صديقي المفضل ستيف،
sensing that something was terribly wrong,
شعر أن هناك خطأ فادح،
flew out to New Haven to be with me.
سافر إلى نيو هافن كي يكون معي.
Now I'm going to quote from some of my writings:
الآن سوف أقتبس بعض من كتاباتي:
"I opened the door to my studio apartment.
فتحت باب شقتي الصغيرة.
Steve would later tell me that,
يخبرني ستيف بعدها بفترة
for all the times he had seen me psychotic, nothing
في كل الأوقات التي رأني فيها مضطربة نفسياً، لا شيء
could have prepared him for what he saw that day.
كان بالإمكان أن يعده لما رآه في ذلك اليوم.
For a week or more, I had barely eaten.
لأكثر من أسبوع لم أكل شيء
I was gaunt. I walked
كنت هزيلة. مشيت
as though my legs were wooden.
كما لو كانت ساقاي خشبيتان.
My face looked and felt like a mask.
و بدا وجهي كالقناع
I had closed all the curtains in the apartment, so
أغلقت جميع الستائر في الشقة
in the middle of the day
و حتى في منتصف النهار
the apartment was in near total darkness.
كانت الشقة في ظلام دامس.
The air was fetid, the room a shambles.
كان الهواء نتن، وكانت الغرفة في حالة فوضى.
Steve, both a lawyer and a psychologist, has treated
قد عالج ستيف، محامي ومرشد نفسي
many patients with severe mental illness, and to this day
العديد من المرضى الذين يعانون من مرض عقلي مزمن، وحتى اليوم
he'll say I was as bad as any he had ever seen.
يقول انني كنت أسوأ من أي شخص رأه في حياته.
'Hi,' I said, and then I returned to the couch,
"قلت : مرحبا، ثم عدت إلى الأريكة،
where I sat in silence for several moments.
حيث جلست في صمت لعدة لحظات.
'Thank you for coming, Steve.
"شكرا لمجيئك، ستيف.
Crumbling world, word, voice.
بصوت يتفتت كلمة كلمة.
Tell the clocks to stop.
قُل للساعات أن تتوقف.
Time is. Time has come.'
الوقت. الوقت قد حان. "
'White is leaving,' Steve said somberly.
"د. وايت سوف يغادر." قال ستيف بإكتئاب
'I'm being pushed into a grave. The situation is grave,' I moan.
"اني اندفع إلى القبر، الوضع مرهب" قلت بأنين.
'Gravity is pulling me down.
"الجاذبية تسحبني إلى الأسفل.
I'm scared. Tell them to get away.'"
أنا خائفة. قل لهم أن يبتعدوا "
As a young woman, I was in a psychiatric hospital
كامرأة شابة، كنت في مستشفى للأمراض النفسية
on three different occasions for lengthy periods.
لثلاث مرات مختلفة لفترات طويلة.
My doctors diagnosed me with chronic schizophrenia,
الأطباء شخصوا حالتي بالفصام المزمن.
and gave me a prognosis of "grave."
وأنذروني بتكهن "خطير"
That is, at best, I was expected to live in a board and care,
وهذا هو، في أحسن الأحوال، وكنت أتوقع أن أعيش في رعاية
and work at menial jobs.
و أعمل في وظائف وضيعة.
Fortunately, I did not actually
لحسن الحظ، لم أكن في الواقع
enact that grave prognosis.
مُصابة بذاك التكهن الخطير.
Instead, I'm a chaired Professor of Law, Psychology
بدلا من ذلك، تقلدت منصب استاذ للحقوق وعلم نفس
and Psychiatry at the USC Gould School of Law,
والطب النفسي في كلية غولد للقانون في جامعة جنوب كالفورنيا
I have many close friends
لدي العديد من الأصدقاء المقربين
and I have a beloved husband, Will, who's here with us today.
و معنا هنا اليوم زوجي الحبيب، اسمه ويل
(Applause) Thank you.
(تصفيق) شكرا لكم.
He's definitely the star of my show.
انه بالتأكيد نجم عرضي.
I'd like to share with you how that happened, and also
أود أن أشارككم كيف حدث ذلك، وأيضا
describe my experience of being psychotic.
أصف تجربتي بالاضطراب النفسي.
I hasten to add that it's my experience,
أسارع الى القول و أضيف بأنها تجربتي،
because everyone becomes psychotic in his or her own way.
لأن الجميع يصبح مضطرب نفسياً  بطريقته.
Let's start with the definition of schizophrenia.
دعونا نبدأ مع تعريف انفصام الشخصية.
Schizophrenia is a brain disease.
انفصام الشخصية هو مرض في الدماغ.
Its defining feature is psychosis, or being
ميزته الذهان أو أن تكون
out of touch with reality.
بعيداً كل البعد عن الواقع.
Delusions and hallucinations
الأوهام والهلوسة
are hallmarks of the illness.
هي السمات المميزة للمرض.
Delusions are fixed and false beliefs that aren't responsive
الأوهام والمعتقدات الثابتة والكاذبة التي لا تستجيب
to evidence, and hallucinations are false sensory experiences.
إلى الأدلة، والهلوسة هي التجارب الحسية الكاذبة.
For example, when I'm psychotic I often have
على سبيل المثال، عندما أكون في إضطراب نفسي غالبا
the delusion that I've killed hundreds of thousands
أكون في وهم أنني قد قتلت مئات الآلاف
of people with my thoughts.
من الناس في فكري.
I sometimes have the idea that
بعض الأحيان لدي فكرة أن
nuclear explosions are about to be set off in my brain.
تفجيرات النووية على وشك أن تفجر في مخي.
Occasionally, I have hallucinations,
في بعض الأحيان، لدي هلوسات،
like one time I turned around and saw a man
مثل مرة  التفت حولي فأرى رجلاً
with a raised knife.
رافعاً سكينة
Imagine having a nightmare while you're awake.
تخيل أنك ترى كابوس و انت مستيقظ.
Often, speech and thinking become disorganized
في كثير من الأحيان، كلامي وتفكيري أصبحا مشوشين
to the point of incoherence.
إلى حد التنافر.
Loose associations involves putting together words
يشمل الترابط المتفكك جمع كلمات
that may sound a lot alike but don't make sense,
قد تبدو متشابهة ولكن لا معنى لها،
and if the words get jumbled up enough, it's called "word salad."
وإذا اختلطت الكلمات  كثيراً، فهذا يدعى "سلطة الكلمة".
Contrary to what many people think, schizophrenia is not
على عكس ما يعتقد كثير من الناس، انفصام الشخصية ليس
the same as multiple personality disorder or split personality.
نفس اضطراب في الشخصية المتعددة أو انفصام الشخصية.
The schizophrenic mind is not split, but shattered.
العقل المنفصم ليس بالمنفصل و لكنه مهشّم
Everyone has seen a street person,
فقد رأى الجميع رجلاً في الشارع
unkempt, probably ill-fed,
غير مهذب، وربما بسوء تغذية،
standing outside of an office building muttering
يقف خارج مبنى وهو يتمتم
to himself or shouting.
بنفسه أو يصرخ.
This person is likely to have some form of schizophrenia.
فعلى الأرجح أن يكون هذا الشخص مصاب بنوع من أنواع انفصام الشخصية
But schizophrenia presents itself across a wide array
ولكن مرض انفصام الشخصية يطرح نفسه عبر مجموعة واسعة
of socioeconomic status, and there are people
من الأوضاع الاجتماعية الاقتصادية، وهناك اناس
with the illness who are full-time professionals
مصابون بالمرض محترفين يعملون بدوام كامل
with major responsibilities.
ويتحملون مسؤوليات كبيرة.
Several years ago, I decided
قررت قبل عدة سنوات
to write down my experiences and my personal journey,
تدوين تجربتي ورحلتي الشخصية،
and I want to share some more of that story with you today
وأريد اليوم أن أشارككم بعض من تلك القصص
to convey the inside view.
لنقل وجهة نظري الداخلية.
So the following episode happened the seventh week
هذه الحلقة حدثت في الأسبوع السابع
of my first semester of my first year at Yale Law School.
من الفصل الدراسي الأول في السنة الأولى في كلية القانون في جامعة ييل.
Quoting from my writings:
نقلا من كتاباتي:
"My two classmates, Rebel and Val, and I had made the date
"كان لي زميلان  ، ريبل  وفال، و اتفقنا
to meet in the law school library on Friday night
أن نلتقي في مكتبة الكلية  ليلة الجمعة
to work on our memo assignment together.
للعمل على تعيين مذكرتنا معا.
But we didn't get far before I was talking in ways
و قبل أن نبدأ. أصبحت أتكلم بالطرق
that made no sense.
التي هي بلا معنى
'Memos are visitations,' I informed them.
"المذكرات هي الزيارات" ابلغتهم .
'They make certain points. The point is on your head.
'تحقق بعض هذه النقاط هدفاً و النقطة في دماغك.
Pat used to say that. Have you killed you anyone?'
ذلك ما كان يقوله بات . أقتلتي أحداً ؟
Rebel and Val looked at me
نظرا ربل وفان إلي
as if they or I had been
وكأن أحداً منا
splashed in the face with cold water.
قد رمي وجهه بالماء البارد
'What are you talking about, Elyn?'
'ما الذي تتحدثين عنه، إلين؟
'Oh, you know, the usual. Who's what, what's who,
"أه، هل تعلمون، كالعادة. الذين ما، ما الذي،
heaven and hell. Let's go out on the roof.
الجنة والنار. دعونا نخرج على السطح.
It's a flat surface. It's safe.'
السطح مستو. و آمن ".
Rebel and Val followed
تبعني ربل وفال
and they asked what had gotten into me.
و سألا ما قد حصل لي.
'This is the real me,' I announced,
"في الحقيقة هذا أنا" قلت لهم.
waving my arms above my head.
رافعة ذراعي فوق رأسي.
And then, late on a Friday night, on the roof
ومن ثم، في وقت متأخر من ليلة الجمعة، على سطح
of the Yale Law School,
كلية الحقوق في جامعة ييل،
I began to sing, and not quietly either.
بدأت بالغناء، وليس بهدوء
'Come to the Florida sunshine bush.
"تعالي إلى فلوريدا أيتها الشمس المشرقة.
Do you want to dance?'
هل ترغب في الرقص؟ "
'Are you on drugs?' one asked. 'Are you high?'
'هل تتعاطين المخدرات؟ "سأل أحد. 'هل أنتي مخدرة؟
'High? Me? No way, no drugs.
'مخدرة  ؟ أنا ؟ مستحيل  ، لا مخدرات.
Come to the Florida sunshine bush,
"تعالي إلى فلوريدا أيتها الشمس المشرقة.
where there are lemons, where they make demons.'
فهناك الليمون و الشياطين"
'You're frightening me,' one of them said, and Rebel and Val
"أنت تخوفني،" قال احدهم، وربل وفل
headed back into the library.
عادا إلى المكتبة.
I shrugged and followed them.
تجاهلت الأمر وتبعتهم.
Back inside, I asked my classmates if they were
عدت الى الداخل، سألت زملائي اذا كانوا
having the same experience of words jumping around
يعانون من نفس التجربة تطاير الكلمات
our cases as I was.
كحالتي.
'I think someone's infiltrated my copies of the cases,' I said.
"أعتقد أن شخصاً ما تسلل ونسخ حالتي" قلت.
'We've got to case the joint.
"لقد وصلنا الى حالة المفصل.
I don't believe in joints, but
أنا لا أعتقد بالمفاصل، ولكن
they do hold your body together.'" --
انهم يعقدون جسمك معاً. "
It's an example of loose associations. --
انها مثال لأصعب الحالات.
"Eventually I made my way back to my dorm room,
أخيراً عدت إلى غرفتي،
and once there, I couldn't settle down.
وهناك لم اتمكن من الإستقرار.
My head was too full of noise,
كان رأسي ممتلئاً بالضجيج،
too full of orange trees and law memos I could not write
وبأشجار البرتقال، والمذكرات القانون لم أتمكن من كتابتها
and mass murders I knew I would be responsible for.
وقتل جماعي كنت أعرف أنني سأكون مسؤولة عنها.
Sitting on my bed, I rocked back and forth,
جلست على سريري اهتز بهدوء
moaning in fear and isolation."
ائن بخوف و عزلة ".
This episode led to my first hospitalization in America.
أدى هذا الحادث إلى استشفائي الأول في أمريكا.
I had two earlier in England.
بعد استشفائي مرتان في انجلترا.
Continuing with the writings:
مواصلة مع الكتابة:
"The next morning I went to my professor's office to ask
"وفي صباح اليوم التالي ذهبت الى مكتب الاستاذ لكي أطلب
for an extension on the memo assignment,
تمديد لإحالة المذكرة،
and I began gibbering unintelligably
وبدأت الثرثرة بغباء
as I had the night before,
كما فعلت في الليلة السابقة،
and he eventually brought me to the emergency room.
أخيراً، احضرني إلى غرفة الطوارئ
Once there, someone I'll just call 'The Doctor'
هناك ، شخصا ما إتصل "بالطبيب"
and his whole team of goons swooped down,
وفريقه الحمقى كلهم توجهوا إلي
lifted me high into the air,
رفعوني عاليا في الهواء،
and slammed me down on a metal bed
والقوني على سرير معدني
with such force that I saw stars.
بقوة لدرجة انني رأيت النجوم
Then they strapped my legs and arms to the metal bed
ثم ربطوا ساقي وذراعي بالسرير المعدني
with thick leather straps.
بأشرطة من الجلد السميك.
A sound came out of my mouth that I'd never heard before:
صدر صوت من فمي لم أسمعه من قبل:
half groan, half scream,
نصف تأوه، نصف صراخ،
barely human and pure terror.
بالكاد إنساني، إرهابي بحت
Then the sound came again,
ثم جاء الصوت مرة أخرى،
forced from somewhere deep inside my belly
بقوة من أعماق جوفي
and scraping my throat raw."
يكاد يسحق حلقي
This incident resulted in my involuntary hospitalization.
أدت هذه الحالة إلى دخولي غير الإرادي إلى المستشفى
One of the reasons the doctors gave for hospitalizing me
كان أحد الأسباب التي أعطاها الاطباء لإقامتي في المستشفى
against my will was that I was
ضد إرادتي هو كوني
"gravely disabled."
"معاقة بخطورة"
To support this view, they wrote in my chart that I was unable
و ليدعموا ذلك فقد كتبوا في ملفي بأنني غير قادرة
to do my Yale Law School homework.
على متابعة دراستي في كلية الحقوق بجامعة ييل
I wondered what that meant about much of the rest of New Haven.
و تسألت عن ما قد يحدث لبقية سكان نيو فيڤن
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
During the next year, I would
و قضيت السنة التالية
spend five months in a psychiatric hospital.
خمسة أشهر في مشفى للأمراض العقلية
At times, I spent up to 20 hours in mechanical restraints,
و بعض الأوقات قضيت ما يقرب ٢٠ ساعة تحت قيود آلية
arms tied, arms and legs tied down,
ذراعيي مقيدة أو ذراعيي و ساقي مقيدين
arms and legs tied down with a net tied
ذراعي و ساقي مقيدين بشبكة
tightly across my chest.
مقيدة حول صدري
I never struck anyone.
لم أضرب أحداً قط.
I never harmed anyone. I never made any direct threats.
لم أؤذي أحد و لم أهدد أحد قط.
If you've never been restrained yourself, you may have
إن لم تتعرض لأن تقيد فقد
a benign image of the experience.
تتخيل الوضع بصورة لطيفة
There's nothing benign about it.
و لكن لا لطف في هذه الصورة
Every week in the United States,
أسبوعياً في الولايات المتحدة
it's been estimated that one to three people die in restraints.
أنه يقدر بوفاة شخص من ثلاثة أشخاص في هذه القيود
They strangle, they aspirate their vomit,
يختنقون من شفط الهواء و يتقيؤن
they suffocate, they have a heart attack.
ينعدم تنفسهم و يصابوا بسكتة قلبية
It's unclear whether using mechanical restraints
إنه ليس من الواضح بأن استعمال القيود الآلية
is actually saving lives or costing lives.
يساعد على النجاة أو يكلف البعض أرواحهم
While I was preparing to write my student note
بينما كنت أستعد لكتابة مذكراتي الدراسية
for the Yale Law Journal on mechanical restraints,
عن القيود الآلية لمجلة الحقوق لجامعة ييل
I consulted an eminent law professor who was also
شاورت استاذ قانون مشهور
a psychiatrist,
و طبيب نفسي في الوقت نفسه
and said surely he would agree
و قال أنه بالتأكيد يوافق
that restraints must be degrading,
أن القيود مهينة
painful and frightening.
مؤلمة و مخيفة.
He looked at me in a knowing way, and said,
نظر إلي بعلم و قال
"Elyn, you don't really understand:
"ايلن، انت لا تفهمين:
These people are psychotic.
إن هؤلاء الناس يعانون من اضطرابات ذهنية
They're different from me and you.
إنهم مختلفون عني و عنك.
They wouldn't experience restraints as we would."
إن تجربتهم للقيود تختلف عن تلك التي قد نمّر بها أنا و انت"
I didn't have the courage to tell him in that moment that,
لم تكن لدي الشجاعة وقتها لأخبره
no, we're not that different from him.
لا، نحن لسنا بمختلفين عنه.
We don't like to be strapped down to a bed
فنحن لا نحب مثله أن نقيّد إلى السرير
and left to suffer for hours any more than he would.
و نترك لنعاني لساعات
In fact, until very recently,
و في الواقع حتى مؤخراً
and I'm sure some people still hold it as a view,
و أنا متأكدة ان البعض له نفس وجهة النظر
that restraints help psychiatric patients feel safe.
أن تقييد مرضى الاضطرابات الذهنية يعد آمناً
I've never met a psychiatric patient
لم أقابل أبداً أي مريض مصاب بالذهان
who agreed with that view.
الذي قد يوافق هذا الرأي
Today, I'd like to say I'm very pro-psychiatry
و أود أن أقول أنني اليوم أوافق الطب النفسي
but very anti-force.
و لكنني ضد الإكراه
I don't think force is effective as treatment, and I think
لا اعتقد أن الإكراه فعّال كعلاج و اعتقد
using force is a terrible thing to do to another person
أن استخدام الإكراه شيء فظيع ضد شخص مصاب
with a terrible illness.
بمرض رهيب
Eventually, I came to Los Angeles
في النهاية جئت إلى لوس انجلوس
to teach at the University of Southern California Law School.
لأدرّس في كلية الحقوق بجامعة جنوب كاليفورنيا
For years, I had resisted medication,
فقد قاومت العقاقير لسنين
making many, many efforts to get off.
و بذلت الكثير من المجهود لتركها
I felt that if I could manage without medication,
شعرت بأنني لو استطعت أن أعيش دون العقاقير
I could prove that, after all,
سأثبت بعد ذلك كله
I wasn't really mentally ill, it was some terrible mistake.
بأنني لم أكن مريضة عقلياً و أنه كان خطأ فادح
My motto was the less medicine, the less defective.
شعاري هو أنه كلما قلت العقاقير كلما قلّ الاختلال
My L.A. analyst, Dr. Kaplan, was urging me
كان محللي في لوس انجلوس يحثني
just to stay on medication and get on with my life,
على المواظبة على العقاقير و متابعة حياتي.
but I decided I wanted to make one last college try to get off.
لكنني أردت محاولة أخرى كتلك في الكلية لترك العقاقير
Quoting from the text:
اقتطف من كتابة :
"I started the reduction of my meds, and within a short time
"بدأت بتخفيف أدويتي و خلال وقت قصير
I began feeling the effects.
بدأت أشعر بالتأثير
After returning from a trip to Oxford, I marched into
بعد رجوعي من رحلة إلى أوكسفورد دخلت
Kaplan's office, headed straight for the corner, crouched down,
مكتب كابلان، متجهة نحو الزاوية و جلست أرضاً
covered my face, and began shaking.
خبأت وجهي و بدأت بالإرتجاف
All around me I sensed evil beings poised with daggers.
شعرت أن حولي كائنات شيطانية بخناجر
They'd slice me up in thin slices
و قطعوني إلى شرائح رفيعة
or make me swallow hot coals.
او انهم أرغموني أن ابتلع الجمر
Kaplan would later describe me as 'writhing in agony.'
وصفني بعدها كابلان بأنني كنت "أتلوى بلوعة"
Even in this state, what he accurately described as
و حتى هذه الحالة ما يصفه بدقة
acutely and forwardly psychotic,
اضطراب ذهني مزمن ومتنامي
I refused to take more medication.
و رفضت تناول المزيد من العقاقير
The mission is not yet complete.
لم تكتمل مهمتي بعد
Immediately after the appointment with Kaplan,
و فور ذلك الموعد مع كابلان
I went to see Dr. Marder, a schizophrenia expert
ذهبت إلى دكتور ماردر. أخصائي الفصام
who was following me for medication side effects.
الذي كان يتابع أعراض العقاقير الجانبية
He was under the impression that I had a mild psychotic illness.
كان يعتقد انني أعاني من مرض ذهني متوسط
Once in his office, I sat on his couch, folded over,
فقد جلست مرة على الأريكة في مكتبه منطوية
and began muttering.
و بدأت بالتمتمة
'Head explosions and people trying to kill.
'انفجارات في رأسي و بعض الناس يحاول القتل
Is it okay if I totally trash your office?'
هل من الممكن أن أ خرب مكتبك؟'
'You need to leave if you think you're going to do that,'
'عليك أن تغادري إن كنت على وشك أن تفعلي ذلك،'
said Marder.
قال ماردر.
'Okay. Small. Fire on ice. Tell them not to kill me.
'حسناً، صغير. نار على ثلج. قل لهم أن لا يقتلوني.'
Tell them not to kill me. What have I done wrong?
قل لهم أن لا يقتلوني. ما الذي أخطأت فعله؟
Hundreds of thousands with thoughts, interdiction.'
مئات الآلاف مع الأفكار ، التحريم.'
'Elyn, do you feel like you're
'ايلن هل تشعرين
dangerous to yourself or others?
بأنك تشكلين خطر على نفسك أو الاخرين؟
I think you need to be in the hospital.
أعتقد أنك بحاجة للبقاء في المستشفى.
I could get you admitted right away, and the whole thing
بإمكاني إدخالك فوراً و الأمر كله
could be very discrete.'
قد يتم بسرية .'
'Ha, ha, ha.
' ها ها ها.
You're offering to put me in hospitals?
تعرض علي أن تدخلني المستشفى؟
Hospitals are bad, they're mad, they're sad.
المستشفيات سيئة و مجنونة و حزينة.
One must stay away. I'm God, or I used to be.'"
يجب على الشخص الإبتعاد عنها. أنا الرب او كنت"
At that point in the text,
في تلك المرحلة في الكتابة
where I said "I'm God, or I used to be," my husband
عندما قلت "أنا الرب او كنت،"
made a marginal note.
أضاف زوجي ملحوظة
He said, "Did you quit or were you fired?"
قال "هل استقلتي ام قاموا برفدك؟"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"'I give life and I take it away.
"أمنح و أخذ الحياة"
Forgive me, for I know not what I do.'
سامحني لأني لا اعرف ما يجب علي فعله.'
Eventually, I broke down in front of friends, and
في النهاية إنهرت أمام الأصدقاء
everybody convinced me to take more medication.
و اقنعني الجميع بتناول المزيد من الأدوية
I could no longer deny the truth,
لم أعد أن أنكر الحقيقة،
and I could not change it.
و لم أستطيع تغييرها
The wall that kept me, Elyn, Professor Saks,
الحائط الذي أعاقني. ايلن، الأستاذة ساكس
separate from that insane woman hospitalized years past,
عن تلك المرأة المجنونة في المستشفى من سنين مضت
lay smashed and in ruins."
حائط مهدم و في انهيار. "
Everything about this illness says I shouldn't be here,
كل شيء يتعلق بهذا المرض يحتم أنني لا يمكن أن اكون هنا،
but I am. And I am, I think, for three reasons:
و لكنني هنا. أنا هنا لثلاثة أسباب:
First, I've had excellent treatment.
اولاً، تلقيت علاج ممتاز.
Four- to five-day-a-week psychoanalytic psychotherapy
٤ إلى ٥ أيام في الاسبوع علاج نفسي تحليلي
for decades and continuing, and excellent psychopharmacology.
لعقود و مستمرة و عقاقير ذهانية مختصة ممتازة
Second, I have many close family members and friends who know me
ثانياً لدي العديد من الأصدقاء و أفراد العائلة المقربين الذين يعرفوني
and know my illness.
و على علم بمرضي
These relationships have given my life a meaning
أعطت هذه العلاقات معنى لحياتي
and a depth, and they also helped me navigate
و عمق و ساعدوني على التعايش
my life in the face of symptoms.
لمواجهة الأعراض
Third, I work at an enormously supportive workplace
و ثالثاً أعمل في مكان عمل داعم
at USC Law School.
في كلية الحقوق في جنوب كالفورنيا
This is a place that not only accommodates my needs
هذا ليس مكان فقط ليتحمل حاجاتي
but actually embraces them.
و لكنه يحيطها برعاية
It's also a very intellectually stimulating place,
و إنه مكان مثير فكرياً
and occupying my mind with complex problems
و يشغل ذهني بقضايا معقدة
has been my best and most powerful and most reliable
و هذا الشيء الاكثر فعالية و تأثير
defense against my mental illness.
للتصدي ضد مرضي النفسي.
Even with all that — excellent treatment, wonderful family and
و مع ذلك كله -- العلاج الممتاز والعائلة الرائعة
friends, supportive work environment —
و الأصدقاء و بيئة العمل الداعمة --
I did not make my illness public
لم أفصح عن مرضي للعامة
until relatively late in life,
حتى مرحلة متأخرة من حياتي،
and that's because the stigma against mental illness
و ذلك بسبب النظرة المعتادة ضد الامراض النفسية
is so powerful that I didn't feel safe with people knowing.
إنها قوية لدرجة أني لم أرتاح لمعرفة البعض بمرضي
If you hear nothing else today,
إن سمعت شيء غير ذلك اليوم
please hear this: There are not "schizophrenics."
إستمع الى هذه النقطة: ليس هناك "المصابين بالفصام"
There are people with schizophrenia, and these people
هناك أشخاص مصابين بالفصام هؤلاء الناس
may be your spouse, they may be your child,
أزواجكم، أو أطفالكم
they may be your neighbor, they may be your friend,
أو جيرانكم أو أصدقائكم
they may be your coworker.
أو زملاء العمل
So let me share some final thoughts.
و أشارككم فكرة أخيرة
We need to invest more resources into research and treatment
علينا أن نستثمر العديد من الموارد في البحوث و العلاج
of mental illness.
للامراض النفسية
The better we understand these illnesses, the better
فكلما تفهمنا هذه الامراض كلما
the treatments we can provide, and the better the treatments
قدمنا علاج أفضل و كلما تحسّن العلاج
we can provide, the more we can offer people care,
كلما تحسنت الرعاية التي نقدمها
and not have to use force.
حيث لا نستخدم الإكراه.
Also, we must stop criminalizing mental illness.
و علينا أن نتوقف عن تجريم المرض النفسي
It's a national tragedy and scandal that the L.A. County Jail
إنها مأساة وطنية أنه في سجن المقاطعة في لوس انجلوس
is the biggest psychiatric facility in the United States.
هو أكبر مصحة للأمراض النفسية في الولايات المتحدة
American prisons and jails are filled with people who suffer
تكتظ السجون و الحبوس الامريكية بالأشخاص الذين يعانون
from severe mental illness, and many of them are there
من أمراض نفسية مزمنة و العديد منهم
because they never received adequate treatment.
ينتهون هناك لأنهم لم يحصلوا على العلاج الملائم.
I could have easily ended up there or on the streets myself.
و من السهل أن ينتهي بي المطاف هناك أو في الشوارع
A message to the entertainment industry and to the press:
رسالة إلى صناعات الترفيه والأفلام و الاعلام:
On the whole, you've done a wonderful job fighting stigma
في المجمل ، لقد بذلتم مجهودا رائعاً في محاربة وصمة العار
and prejudice of many kinds.
والأحكام المسبقة بأنواعها المتعددة
Please, continue to let us see characters in your movies,
أرجوكم، استمروا في عرض الشخصيات في أفلامكم
your plays, your columns,
و مسرحياتكم و مجلاتكم
who suffer with severe mental illness.
من الذين يعانون من أمراض نفسية مزمنة
Portray them sympathetically,
اعرضوهم بتعاطف
and portray them in all the richness and depth
وقدموا تجاربهم بعمق و معنى
of their experience as people and not as diagnoses.
كأشخاص و ليسوا مجرد تشخيصات.
Recently, a friend posed a question:
مؤخراً، سألني صديق:
If there were a pill I could take
إن كان هناك حبة أبتلعها
that would instantly cure me, would I take it?
لتشفيني فوراً، هل لكنت أتناولها؟
The poet Rainer Maria Rilke
عُرض على الشاعر رينر ماريا ريلك
was offered psychoanalysis.
تحليل نفسي
He declined, saying, "Don't take my devils away,
رفضه ، قائلاً "لا تأخذ بشياطيني بعيداً
because my angels may flee too."
لأن ملائكتي قد تهرب ايضاً"
My psychosis, on the other hand,
ان فصامي من جهة أخرى
is a waking nightmare in which my devils are so terrifying
هو كابوس يقظ فيه شياطيني مخيفة جداً
that all my angels have already fled.
بحيث هربت منه جميع ملائكتي
So would I take the pill? In an instant.
لذا سأتناول تلك الحبة بلمحة عين
That said, I don't wish to be seen as regretting
و مع قولي ذلك لا أريد أن أندم
the life I could have had if I'd not been mentally ill,
على حياة قد عشتها دون ان اكون مريضة نفسياً
nor am I asking anyone for their pity.
و لا أسأل الشفقة من أحد.
What I rather wish to say is that the humanity we all share
و ما أتمناه أننا بكل الانسانية التي نشترك فيها
is more important than the mental illness we may not.
أكثر أهمية من المرض النفسي الذي لا نشترك به.
What those of us who suffer with mental illness want
إن ما يريده هؤلاء الذين يعانون من الامراض النفسية
is what everybody wants:
هو كل ما يريده الجميع:
in the words of Sigmund Freud, "to work and to love."
كلمات سيجموند فرويد "أن نعمل و نعشق"
Thank you. (Applause)
شكراً (تصفيق)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you. Thank you. You're very kind. (Applause)
شكراً. شكراً. هذا لطف منكم (تصفيق)
Thank you. (Applause)
شكراً (تصفيق)